Finding Aid for the Evelyn Caldwell Hooker Papers LSC.0523
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Books
  - Books not previously owned by UCLA libraries, 1925-1982. (Box 9)
    - Carling, Finn. And yet we are human. London: Chatto & Windus, 1962. [Author's autograph presentation copy; with dust jacket]. (Box 9)
    - Jersild, Jens. De pædofile. Københaven: Nyt Nordisk Forlag Arnold Busck, 1964. [Author's autograph presentation copy; with dust jacket]. (Box 9)
    - Moffatt, James. The New Testament: a New Translation. New York: Association Press, 1925. [Annotated: From Aase George, June 1930, The Beginning of My Education; with Evelyn Gentry ex libris]. (Box 9)
    - Robinson, Kenneth. Patterns of Care. London: National Association for Mental Health, 1961. [Author's autograph presentation copy]. (Box 9)
    - Roestvig, Maren-Sofie. The Happy Man: Studies in the Metamorphoses of a Classical Ideal 1600-1700. Oslo: Akademisk Forlag; Oxford: Basil Blackwell, 1954. [Author's autograph presentation copy of publisher's advance copy]. (Box 9)
    - Silverstein, Charles. A Family Matter: A Parents' Guide to Homosexuality. New York: McGraw-Hill Book Company, c. 1977. [Author's autograph presentation copy; with dust jacket]. (Box 9)
    - Townsend, Larry. The Leatherman's Handbook. New York: The Other Traveller, c. 1982. [Author's autograph presentation copy]. (Box 9)
    - Zambucka, Kristin. Ano Ano: the Seed. Honolulu, Hawaii: Mana Publishing Company, c. 1978. [Inscribed copy to Evelyn Hooker from Carole]. (Box 9)
  - Variant editions of books owned by UCLA libraries, 1924-1994. (Box 10)
    - Defiant Desire: Gay and Lesbian Lives in South Africa. Mark Gevisser and Edwin Cameron, eds. Johannesburg: Raven Press, c. 1994. [Author's autograph presentation copy; paperback]. (Box 10)
    - Benjamin, Harry. The Transsexual Phenomenon. New York: Julian Press, c1966. With: Supplement. [With dust jacket]. (Box 10)
    - Bradbury, Ray. The Illustrated Man. Garden City, New York: Doubleday & Company, 1953. [Author's autograph presentation copy; with dust jacket]. (Box 10)
    - Freeman, Joseph. An American Testament: A Narrative of Rebels and Romantics. London: Wictor Gollanz Limited, 1938. Left Book Club edition [Inscription by Jim Cottle]. (Box 10)
    - Greenwald, Harold. The Call Girl: A Social And Psychoanalytic Study. New York: Ballantine Books, c. 1958. [Author's autograph presentation copy, 1961]. (Box 10)
    - Kelley, Truman L. Statistical Method. New York: The Macmillan Company, 1924. [Karl F. Muenzinger's copy; with marginalia in pencil]. (Box 10)
    - Marlowe, Kenneth. Mr. Madam: Confessions of a Male Madam. Los Angeles: Sherbourne Press, c. 1964. [Author's autograph presentation copy; with dust jacket]. (Box 10)
    - Pomeroy, Wardell B. Boys & Sex: A Long-Needed Modern Sexual Guide for Boys. New York: Delacorte Press, c. 1968. [Author's autograph presntation copy; with dust jacket]. (Box 10)
    - West, D.J. Homosexuality. [Harmondsworth, Middlesex]: Penguin Books, c. 1960 [Paperback]. (Box 10)
    - Wildeblood, Peter. Against the Law. New York: Julian Messner, c. 1959. [With dust jacket]. (Box 10)
  - Copies of books owned by UCLA libraries, 1929-1981. (Box 11)
    - Anomaly. The Invert: His Social Adjustment. Baltimore: The Williams & Wilkins Company, c. 1929 [Franklin Fearing's copy] [ORION 0115983SR]. (Box 11)
    - Bayer, Ronald. Homosexuality and American Psychiatry: The Politics of Disgnosis. New York: Basic Books, c. 1981. [Marginalia in ink throughout; with dust jacket]. (Box 11)
    - Boring, Edwin G. The Physical Dimensions of Consciousness. New York: The century Company, c. 1933. [Karl F. Muenzinger's copy; annotations and underlining in pencil throughout]. (Box 11)
    - Brown, J.F. Psychology and the Social Order. New York: McGraw-Hill Company, 1936. [Ex libris Evelyn G. Caldwell; ex libris Evelyn Caldwell Hooker]. (Box 11)
    - California Department of Mental Hygiene. Final report on California Sexual Deviation Research: March 1954. Sacramento: Assembly of the State of California, c. 1954 [Evelyn C. Hooker's copy]. (Box 11)
    - Christie, Richard and Florence L. Geis. Studies in Machiavellianism. New York: Acadmic Press, 1970. [Author's autograph presentation copy; with dust jacket]. (Box 11)
    - Churchill, Wainwright. Homosexual Behavior Among Males: A Cross-Cultural and Cross Species Investigation. New York: Hawthorn Books, c. 1967 [Underlining in ink throughout]. (Box 11)
    - Fear No More: A Book of Poems for the Present Time by Living English Poets. Cambridge, England: At the University Press, 1940 [Copy inscribed to Evelyn C. Hooker; with dust jacket]. (Box 11)
    - Freedman, Mark. Homosexuality and Psychological Functioning. Belmont, California: Brooks/Cole, c. 1971 [Author's autograph presentation copy; paperback]. (Box 11)
  - Copies of books owned by UCLA libraries, 1937-1994. (Box 12)
    - Edwardes, Allen and R.E.L. Masters. The Cradle of Erotica. New York: Julian Press, 1962. Review copy; marginalia [ORION 2723442MC]. (Box 12)
    - Garnets, Linda D. and Douglas C. Kimmel, Eds. Psychological Perspectives on Lesbian and Gay Experiences. New York: Columbia University Press, c. 1993. [Authors' autograph presentation copy; paperback] [ORION 5408901MC]. (Box 12)
    - Goudge, Elizabeth. The Child from the Sea. New York: Howard-McCann, c. 1970. Inscription from her mother to Evelyn C. Hooker [ORION 2956058MC]. (Box 12)
    - Gullans, Charles. Arrivals & Departures. Minneapolis: University of Minnesota Press, c. 1962. Author's autograph presentation copy; with dust jacket [ORION 4108342MC]. (Box 12)
    - Herdt, Gilbert and Andrew Boxer. Children of Horizons: How Gay and Lesbian Teens Are Leading a New Way Out of the Closet. Boston: Beacon Press, c. 1993. Authors' autograph presentation copy; with dust jacket. [ORION 5395089MC]. (Box 12)
    - Hoffman, Martin. The Gay World: Male Homosexuality and the Social Creation of Evil. New York: Basic Books, c. 1968. Evelyn C. Hooker's copy; with dust jacket [ORION 2715745MC]. (Box 12)
    - Human Sexuality: New Directions in American Catholic Thought. New York: Paulist Press, c. 1977. Presentation copy inscribed by Ron Modras to Evelyn C. Hooker; with dust jacket [ORION 2122979MC]. (Box 12)
    - Iga, Mamoru. The Thorn in the Chrysanthemum: Suicide and Economic Success in Modern Japan. Berkeley: University of California Press, c. 1986. Author's autograph presentation copy; with dust jacket [ORION 3186859MC]. (Box 12)
    - Institute for Sex Research. Sexual Behavior in the Human Female. Philadelphia: W.B. Saunders and Company, 1953. Evelyn C. Hooker's copy; marginalia [ORION 2126681MC]. (Box 12)
    - Jersild, Jens. The Normal Homosexual Male vs. the Boy Molester. Copenhagen: Nyt Nordisk Forlag Arnold Busck, 1967. Author's autograph presentation copy [ORION 2716068MC]. (Box 12)
    - Karlen, Arno. Sexuality and Homosexuality: A New View. New York: W.W. Norton & Company, c. 1971. Marginalia and underlining throughout [ORION 2724948MC]. (Box 12)
    - Kinsey, Alfred C., Wardell B. Pomeroy, and Clyde E. Martin. Sexual Behavior in the Human Male. Philadelphia: W.B. Saunders Company, 1948. 7th printing. Evelyn C. Hooker's copy [ORION 2725022MC]. (Box 12)
    - Kluckhohn, Clyde and Henry A. Murray. Personality in Nature, Society, and Culture. New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1949. Franklin Fearing's copy; marginalia; with dust jacket [ORION 3371469MC]. (Box 12)
    - Legg, W. Dorr. Homophile Studies in Theory and Practice. Los Angeles: ONE Institute Press; San Francisco: GLB Publishers, c. 1994. Author's autograph presentation copy; with dust jacket [ORION 5576547MC]. (Box 12)
    - McWhirter, David P. and Andrew M. Mattison. The Male Couple: How Relationships Developed. Englewood Cliffs, New Jersey: Prentice-Hall, c. 1984. Author's autograph presentation copy; with dust jacket [ORION 2421096MC]. (Box 12)
    - Mercer, J.D. They Walk in Shadow. New York: Comet Press Books, c. 1959. Author's autograph presentation copy; special authors copy no. 99; with dust jacket [ORION 2720372MC]. (Box 12)
    - Moore, Kate Gordon. Chapters on the theory of imagination [Los Angeles(?): s.n], c. 1949. Author's autograph presentation copy [ORION 3483909MC]. (Box 12)
    - Myers, Charles S. In the Realm of Mind: Nine Chapters on the Applications and Implications of Psychology. Cambridge, England: At the University Press, 1937. Author's autograph presentation copy to Evelyn Gentry [ORION 5706473MC]. (Box 12)
    - Peters, Edward. Strategy and Tactics in Labor Negotiations. New London, Connecticut: National Foreman's Institute, c. 1955. Author's autograph presentation copy; with dust jacket [ORION 4009336MC]. (Box 12)
  - Copies of books owned by UCLA libraries, 1936-1993. (Box 13)
    - Rechy, John. This Day's Death: A Novel. New York: Grove Press, c. 1969. Author's autograph presentation copy; with dust jacket [ORION 2209614MC]. (Box 13)
    - Rechy, John. The Fourth Angel. New York: Viking Press, c. 1972. Author's autograph presentation copy; with dust jacket [variant edition to ORION 4174189MC]. (Box 13)
    - Rechy, John. Numbers. New York: Grove Press, c. 1967. Author's autograph presentation copy; with dust jacket [variant edition to ORION 4174627MC]. (Box 13)
    - Rechy, John. The Sexual Outlaw: A Documentary. New York: Grove Press, c. 1977. Author's autograph presentation copy; with dust jacket [ORION 2209613MC]. (Box 13)
    - Rechy, John. The Vampires. New York: Grove Press, c. 1971. Author's autograph presentation copy [ORION 2984343MC]. (Box 13)
    - Reinisch, June M. with Ruth Beasley. The Kinsey Institute New Report on Sex: What you Must Know to be Sexually Literate. New York: St. Marten's Press, 1990. Author's autograph presentation copy; with dust jacket [ORION 4957237MC]. (Box 13)
    - Reinisch, June Machover et al, Eds. Masculinity/Femininity: Basic Perspectives. New York: Oxford University Press, 1987. Author's autograph presentation copy; with dust jacket [ORION 4111923MC]. (Box 13)
    - Robinson, Forrest G. Love's Story Told: A Life of Henry A. Murray. Cambridge, Massachusetts: Harvard University press, 1992. Author's autograph presentation copy; with dust jacket [ORION 5254608MC]. (Box 13)
    - Schur, Edwin M. Crimes Without Victims: Deviant Behavior and Public Policy; Abortion, Homosexuality, Drug Addiction. Englewood Cliffs, New Jersey: Prentice-Hall, c. 1965. Evelyn C. Hooker's copy; some marginalia; paperback [ORION 2733077MC]. (Box 13)
    - Seuss, Dr. You're Only Old Once! New York: Random House, c1986. Insribed from Bryan Englund to Evelyn C. Hooker; with dust jacket]. (Box 13)
    - Sherwood, Robert Emmet. Idiot's Delight. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1936. Inscription from Ed Hooker to Evelyn C. Hooker [ORION 2229953MC]. (Box 13)
    - Shneidman, Edwin S. Definition of Suicide. New York: John Wiley & Sons, c. 1985. Author's autograph presentation copy; with dust jacket. (Box 13)
    - Shneidman, Edwin S. Suicide as Psychache: A Clinical Approach to Self-Destructive Behavior. Northvale, New Jersey: Jason Aronson, c. 1993. Author's autograph presentation copy; paperback. (Box 13)
    - Shneidman, Edwin S. Thematic Test Analysis. New York: Grune & Stratton, 1951. Evelyn C. Hooker's copy. (Box 13)
    - Shneidman, Edwin S. Voices of Death. New York: Harper & Row, c. 1980. Author's autograph presentation copy; with dust jacket. (Box 13)
    - Society of Medical Psychoanalysis. Homosexuality: a Psychoanalytic Study. New York: Basic Books, c. 1962. Evelyn C. Hooker's copy; some marginalia; with dust jacket [ORION 2718926MC]. (Box 13)
    - Stewart, David A. Preface to Empathy. New York: Philosophical Library, c1956. Author's autograph presentation copy; with dust jacket [ORION 4165246MC]. (Box 13)
    - Tobey, Mark. Paintings from the Collection of Joyce and Arthur Dahl. Palo Alto: Leland Stanford Art Gallery, Stanford University, c. 1967. Inscribed from Arthur L. Dahl to Evelyn C. Hooker; paperback. (Box 13)
    - Voeller, Bruce, June reinisch, and Michael Gottlieb, Eds. AIDS and Sex: An Integrated Biomedical and Biobehavioral Approach. New York: Oxford University Press, 1990. Author's (Reinisch) autograph presentation copy; with dust jacket [ORION 4993408MC]. (Box 13)
    - Warren, Carol A.B. Identity and Community in the Gay World. New York: John Wiley & Sons, c. 1974. Author's autograph presentation copy; with dust jacket. (Box 13)
    - Welch, Julie and Louise Brody. Leading Men. New York: Villard Books, c. 1985. Inscription from Bryan Englund to Evelyn C. Hooker, 1986; with dust jacket. (Box 13)
    - Wolff, Charlotte. Love Between Women. 2nd ed. London: Duckworth, 1973. Author's autograph presentation copy; paperback. (Box 13)
    - Wysor, Bettie. The Lesbian Myth. New York: Random House, c. 1974. Author's autograph presentation copy; with dust jacket. (Box 13)